Lemasters mss., 1944-1945 LMC 2698
Lilly Library
Lemasters mss.
1944-1945
2009
Lilly Library
Lemasters, Paul, 1913-1995
LMC 2698
1 Box 1 standard
The Lemasters mss., ca. 1944–1945, consists of the correspondence between Lt. Col. Paul R. Lemasters, 1913-1995, and his family in Shelbyville, Indiana, during his World War II service in New Guinea and the South Pacific. Also included are 3 mimeo–based newspapers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Paul R. Lemasters, 1913-1995, was born in Shelbyville, Indiana and served as a lieutenant colonel in the United States Army in World War II. While commanding the 151st Infantry—HQ. 2nd Battalion, he participated in operations securing Manila Bay, including the Fort Hughes Operation and the assault on Fort Drum.
Arrangement
The collection consists of correspondence in chronological order and 1 folder of newsletters.
Scope and Content Note
The correspondence is organized into chronological order, with one miscellaneous folder with correspondence possibly written by others. In addition, there is one folder of newsletters regarding WWII.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2009
Lemasters, Paul, 1913-1995
- 1940-1943 (Box 1)
- Jan 1944 (Box 1)
- Feb 1944 (Box 1)
- Mar 1944 (Box 1)
- Apr 1944 (Box 1)
- May 1944 (Box 1)
- June 1944 (Box 1)
- July 1944 (Box 1)
- Aug 1944 (Box 1)
- Sept 1944 (Box 1)
- Oct 1944 (Box 1)
- Nov 1944 (Box 1)
- Dec 1944 (Box 1)
- Jan 1945 (Box 1)
- Feb 1945 (Box 1)
- Mar 1945 (Box 1)
- Apr 1945 (Box 1)
- May 1945 (Box 1)
- June 1945 (Box 1)
- July 1945 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: misc (Box 1)
- Newsletters (Box 1)